{
    "name": "Basketball",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What was Basketball originally played with?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Soccer Ball",
            "answers": [
                "Soccer Ball",
                "Dodgeball",
                "Hacky Sack",
                "Crumpled up Piece of Paper"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "What was banned between 1968 and 1976?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Slam Dunk",
            "answers": [
                "Slam Dunk",
                "Dribbling",
                "Full Court Throw",
                "3 Pointers"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Michael Jordan was fined for wearing Air Jordan shoes?",
            "type": "tf",
            "correct": "True",
            "answers": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first player in NBA history to reach 30,000 points and 6,000 assists?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Kobe Bryant",
            "answers": [
                "Kobe Bryant",
                "Michael Jordan",
                "Larry Bird",
                "Dennis Rodman"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player has only made one 3 pointer in his NBA career?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Shaquille O’Neal",
            "answers": [
                "Shaquille O’Neal",
                "Bill Russell",
                "Wilt Chamberlain",
                "Paul Arizin"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player won Olympic Gold Medal for USA in 2000?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Vince Carter",
            "answers": [
                "Vince Carter",
                "Dwight Howard",
                "Dwyane Wade",
                "Kevin Garnett"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which NBA player was given the nickname, \"The Big Ticket\"?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Kevin Garnett",
            "answers": [
                "Kevin Garnett",
                "Kobe Bryant",
                "Moses Malone",
                "Stephen Curry"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player spent 18 seasons in the NBA with the Utah Jazz?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Karl Malone",
            "answers": [
                "Karl Malone",
                "John Collins",
                "Jordan Clarkson",
                "Walker Kessler"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was  the first player in NBA history to average a triple-double for an entire season, with 30.8 points, 12.5 rebounds and 11.4 assists?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Oscar Robertson",
            "answers": [
                "Oscar Robertson",
                "Moses Malone",
                "Jerry West",
                "Hakeem Olajuwon"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the two-time NBA Most Valuable Player (2001-2002 and 2002-2003)?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Tim Duncan",
            "answers": [
                "Tim Duncan",
                "Shaquille O'Neal",
                "Jason Kidd",
                "Kobe Bryant"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player was nicknamed 'The Big Dipper'?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Wilt Chamberlain",
            "answers": [
                "Wilt Chamberlain",
                "Bill Russell",
                "Magic Johnson",
                "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only NBA player to score 4,000 points in a season?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Wilt Chamberlain",
            "answers": [
                "Wilt Chamberlain",
                "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
                "Magic Johnson",
                "Bill Russell"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player was the first overall pick of the 2003 NBA draft?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "LeBron James",
            "answers": [
                "LeBron James",
                "Darko Miličić",
                "Carmelo Anthony",
                "Chris Bosh"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player studied the martial art of Jeet Kune Do under Bruce Lee?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
            "answers": [
                "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
                "James Johnson",
                "Taky Kimura ",
                "Brandon Lee"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player is best friends with fellow NBA player Michael Beasley who he grew up with?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Kevin Durant",
            "answers": [
                "Kevin Durant",
                "Joel Anthony",
                "Marcus Banks",
                "Dwyane Wade"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player holds the record for the most three pointers in one game?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Stephen Curry",
            "answers": [
                "Stephen Curry",
                "Ray Allen",
                "James Harden",
                "Reggie Miller"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player holds the NBA single-game record for most rebounds in a half?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Bill Russell",
            "answers": [
                "Bill Russell",
                "Wilt Chamberlain",
                "Elvin Hayes",
                "Moses Malone"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player has been an HIV/AIDS advocate since the 80's?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Magic Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Magic Johnson",
                "Michael Jordan",
                "Shaquille O’Neal",
                "Hakeem Olajuwon"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player holds the NBA record for blocked shots (3,830) and is the only player to record more than 3,000 blocked shots and 2,000 steals in a career?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Hakeem Olajuwon",
            "answers": [
                "Hakeem Olajuwon",
                "Anthony Davis",
                "Evan Mobley",
                "Evan Mobley"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player was the head coach of the Los Angeles Lakers in the 1970's?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Jerry West",
            "answers": [
                "Jerry West",
                "Pat Riley",
                "Magic Johnson",
                "Bill Bertka"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player was a 3 time All-Star, a 6 time rebounding champion, a 3 time league MVP?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Moses Malone",
            "answers": [
                "Moses Malone",
                "Michael Jordan",
                "LeBron James",
                "Julius Erving"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "This player was the NBA Most Valuable Player (MVP) in 1995?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "David Robinson",
            "answers": [
                "David Robinson",
                "Michael Jordan",
                "Mitch Richmond",
                "Karl Malone"
            ]
        }
    ]
}